<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.kde.gcompris.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0+</project_license>
  <name>GCompris Educational Game</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Joc educatiu GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">Joc educatiu GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">GCompris-Lernspiel</name>
  <name xml:lang="el">Εκπαιδευτικό παιχνίδι GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">GCompris Educational Game</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Juego educativo GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="et">Hariv mäng GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">GCompris, opettavainen peli</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Jeu éducatif GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">Xogo educativo GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="hi">जीकोंप्रिस शेक्षणिक अनुप्रयोग</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">GCompris Permainan Edukatif</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">Gioco didattico GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">GCompris 교육용 게임</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Educatief spel GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="nn">GCompris leik-og-lær-spel</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">Gra edukacyjna GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Jogo Educativo GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">Jogo educacional GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="ro">Jocul educațional GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">Набор обучающих игр GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Výuková hra GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">Izobraževalna igra GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">GCompris pedagogiskt spel</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">GCompris Eğitici Oyun</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Освітня гра GCompris</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxGCompris Educational Gamexx</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-CN">GCompris 教育游戏</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-TW">GCompris 教育遊戲</name>
  <summary>Multi-Activity Educational game for children 2 to 10</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Joc educatiu amb múltiples activitats per a nens dels 2 a 10 anys</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Joc educatiu amb múltiples activitats per a nens dels 2 a 10 anys</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Lernspiel mit vielen Aktivitäten für Kinder von 2 bis 10 Jahren</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="el">Εκπαιδευτικό παιχνίδι πολλαπλών δραστηριοτήτων για ηλικίες 2 έως 10 ετών</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">Multi-Activity Educational game for children 2 to 10</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Juego educativo multiactividad para niños de 2 a 10 años</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="et">Rohkete tegevustega hariv mäng lastele vanuses 2-10</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Useampitoimintoinen opettavainen peli 2–10-vuotiaille lapsille</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Jeu éducatif multi-activités pour les enfants de 2 à 10 ans</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Xogo educativo con varias actividades para nenos de entre 2 e 10 anos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hi">२ से १० वर्ष के बच्चों के लिओ विभिन्न क्रियाओं वाला शेक्षणिक खेल</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Permainan Edukatif Multi Aktivitas untuk anak berusia 2 sampai 10 tahun</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Gioco didattico multi-attività per bambini da 2 a 10 anni</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">2-10세 어린이를 위한 다양한 활동이 있는 교육용 게임</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Educatief spel met meerdere activiteiten voor kinderen van 2 tot 10</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nn">Leik-og-lærspel med mange aktivitetar – for barn frå 2 til 10 år</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Gra edukacyjna z wieloma aktywnościami dla dzieci w wieku od 2 do 10 lat</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Jogo Educativo Multi-Actividades para crianças dos 2 aos 10 anos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Jogo educacional com várias atividades para crianças de 2 a 10 anos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ro">Joc educațional cu activități multiple pentru copii între 2 și 10 ani</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ru">Интерактивные обучающие игры для детей от 2 до 10 лет</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Viac-aktivitová výuková hra pre deti od 2 do 10 rokov</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Izobraževalna igra z več dejavnostmi za otroke med drugim in desetim letom starosti</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Pedagogiskt multiaktivitetsspel för barn från 2 till 10 år</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">2 ile 10 yaş arasındaki çocuklar için çok Etkinlikli oyun</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Набір освітніх ігор для дітей від 2 до 10 років</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxMulti-Activity Educational game for children 2 to 10xx</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-CN">为 2 到 10 岁儿童准备的多功能教育游戏</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-TW">為 2-10 歲孩子設計的教育遊戲</summary>
  <description>
    <p>GCompris is a high quality educational software suite, including a large number of activities for children aged 2 to 10.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El GCompris és una suite de programari educatiu d'alta qualitat, que inclou una gran quantitat d'activitats per a nens i nenes entre els 2 i els 10 anys.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">El GCompris és una suite de programari educatiu d'alta qualitat, que inclou una gran quantitat d'activitats per a nens i nenes entre els 2 i els 10 anys.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">GCompris ist eine Lernsoftware mit vielen Aktivitäten für Kinder im Alter von 2 bis 10 Jahren.</p>
    <p xml:lang="el">Το GCompris είναι μια σουίτα εκπαιδευτικού λογισμικού με πολυάριθμες δραστηριότητες για παιδιά ηλικίας 2 έως 10 ετών.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">GCompris is a high quality educational software suite, including a large number of activities for children aged 2 to 10.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">GCompris es un conjunto de programas educativos de alta calidad que contiene un gran número de actividades para niños entre 2 y 10 años.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">GCompris est un logiciel éducatif qui propose des activités variées aux enfants de 2 à 10 ans. Il est plébiscité par les écoles maternelles et primaires de part sa qualité et son spectre couvrant les cycles 1, 2 et 3.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">GCompris é unha colección de programas educativos que inclúe numerosas actividades para nenas e nenos de entre 2 e 10 anos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hi">जीकॉम्परी एक शैक्षिक सॉफ्टवेयर सूट है जिसमें 2 से 10 वर्ष की आयु के बच्चों के लिए कई गतिविधियां शामिल हैं।</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">GCompris adalah kumpulan permainan mendidik yang berisi berbagai kegiatan untuk anak umur 2 sampai dengan 10 Tahun.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">GCompris è una raccolta di alta qualità di programmi didattici che comprende numerose attività per bambini da 2 a 10 anni.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">GCompris is een educatieve software suite van hoge kwaliteit die bestaat uit vele activiteiten voor kinderen vanaf twee tot tien jaar.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nn">GCompris er eit leik og lær-spel med mange ulike aktivitetar for ungar frå 2 til 10 år.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">GCompris to wysokiej jakości pakiet oprogramowania edukacyjnego z licznymi aktywnościami dla dzieci w wieku od 2 do 10 lat.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O GCompris é um pacote de aplicações educativas que é composto por diversas actividades para as crianças dos 2 aos 10 anos de idade.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">GCompris é uma suíte de software educacional de alta qualidade que inclui um grande número de atividades para crianças com idade entre 2 e 10 anos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ro">GCompris este un pachet de software educațional compus din numeroase activități pentru copii între 2 și 10 ani.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">GCompris — большая коллекция обучающих игр и упражнений для детей от 2 до 10 лет.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">GCompris je balík výukového softvéru zložený z rôznych aktivít pre deti od 2 do 10 rokov.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Program GCompris je visokokakovostna izobraževalna zbirka, sestavljena iz velikega števila dejavnosti, ki so namenjena otrokom med drugim in desetim letom starosti.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">GCompris är en högkvalitativ pedagogisk programvarusvit som innehåller ett stort antal aktiviteter för barn mellan 2 och 10 år.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">GCompris, 2 ile 10 yaş arasındaki çocuklar için çok sayıda etkinlik içeren bir eğitim yazılımı paketidir.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">GCompris — високоякісний комплекс навчального програмного забезпечення, що складається з багатьох вправ для дітей від 2 до 10 років.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxGCompris is a high quality educational software suite, including a large number of activities for children aged 2 to 10.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">GCompris 是一套教育軟體的集合，它提供適合兩歲到十歲兒童各種不同的活動。</p>
    <p>Some of the activities are game orientated, but nonetheless
    still educational.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Algunes de les activitats estan orientades a joc, però sempre són educatives.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Algunes de les activitats estan orientades a joc, però sempre són educatives.</p>
    <p xml:lang="cs">Některé aktivity jsou v podobě her, ale přesto jsou poučné.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Einige Aktivitäten sind eher spielerisch, aber immer lehrreich.</p>
    <p xml:lang="el">Ορισμένες από τις δραστηριότητες είναι απλώς παιχνίδια, αλλά οπωσδήποτε με εκπαιδευτικό χαρακτήρα.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Some of the activities are game orientated, but nonetheless still educational.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Algunas de las actividades son juegos, aunque siguen siendo educativas.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Mõned tegevused on mängulisemad, aga siiski õppeotstarbega.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Jotkin toiminnoista ovat pelimäisiä mutta silti opettavaisia.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Certaines activités sont ludiques mais ont toujours un intérêt pédagogique.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Algunhas das actividades están orientadas a xogar pero son tamén educativas.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hi">कुछ गतिविधियां खेल केंद्रित हैं, लेकिन फिर भी शैक्षिक हैं।</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Beberapa aktivitas mengacu ke permainan, namun tetap saja mendidik.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Alcune delle attività sono orientate al gioco, ma comunque didattiche.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">일부 활동은 기능성 게임을 지향합니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Sommige activiteiten zijn spelletjes, maar toch leerzaam.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nn">Nokre av aktivitetane er mest som spel, men er likevel lærerike.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Niektóre z aktywności są bardziej grą, lecz nadal bardzo pouczającą.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Algumas das actividades são apresentadas como jogos, mas são educativas à mesma.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Algumas das atividades são de orientação lúdica, mas mesmo assim ainda educacional.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ro">Unele activități sunt orientate pe joacă, dar totuși educative.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">Некоторые из заданий представлены в игровой форме, но и они являются обучающими.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Niektoré z aktivít sú herne orientované, ale stále výukové.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Nekatere dejavnosti so bolj podobne igram, vendar še vedno poučne.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Vissa av aktiviteterna är spelorienterade, men trots det ändå pedagogiska.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Bazı etkinlikler oyun odaklıdır, ancak yine de eğiticidir.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Деякі із вправ є суто ігровими, але містять і елементи навчання.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxSome of the activities are game orientated, but nonetheless still educational.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">一些活动是游戏导向的，不过尽管如此仍是教育性的。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">有些活動是遊戲性質，但還是有很棒的教育意義。</p>
    <p>Below you can find a list of categories with some of the
    activities available in that category.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">A continuació trobareu una llista de les categories amb algunes de les activitats disponibles en cadascuna.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">A continuació trobareu una llista de les categories amb algunes de les activitats disponibles en cadascuna.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Sie können Aktivitäten aus folgenden Bereichen in GCompris finden:</p>
    <p xml:lang="el">Παρακάτω θα βρείτε μια λίστα με κατηγορίες που περιέχουν ορισμένες από το σύνολο των δραστηριοτήτων σε κάθε κατηγορία.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Below you can find a list of categories with some of the activities available in that category.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">A continuación puede encontrar una lista de categorías con algunas de las actividades disponibles en cada una de ellas.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Allpool leiab kategooriate loetelu koos mõningate neile omaste tegevustega.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Alta löydät luettelot luokista sekä maininnan joistakin kuhunkin luokkaan kuuluvista toiminnoista.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Vous pouvez trouver ci-dessous une liste des catégories avec certaines de leurs activités.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">A continuación pode atopar unha lista de categorías con algunhas das actividades que hai dispoñíbeis en cada categoría.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hi">नीचे आप उस श्रेणी में उपलब्ध कुछ गतिविधियों के साथ श्रेणियों की एक सूची पा सकते हैं।</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Di bawah ini kamu dapat menemukan daftar kategori-kategori dengan beberapa aktivitas-aktivitas yang tersedia dalam kategori tersebut.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Di seguito puoi trovare un elenco di categorie con alcune delle attività disponibili per categoria.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">아래에서 분류 목록과 해당 분류의 활동을 찾을 수 있습니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Hieronder vindt u een lijst met categorieën met enige van de activiteiten beschikbaar in die categorie.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nn">Nedanfor finn du ei oversikt over kategoriar, saman med nokre av aktivitetane i kvar kategori.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Poniżej znajdziesz wykaz kategorii z niektórymi aktywnościami dostępnymi w tej kategorii.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Em baixo, poderá encontrar uma lista de categorias, com algumas das actividades disponíveis para essa categoria.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Abaixo está relacionada uma lista de categorias com algumas das atividades disponíveis em cada uma delas.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ro">Dedesubt puteți găsi o listă de categorii cu unele din activitățile disponibile în acea categorie.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">Ниже представлен список категорий с доступными в этих категориях заданиями.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Tu môžete nájsť zoznam kategórií s niektorými aktivitami dostupnými v kategórii.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Spodaj lahko najdete seznam kategorij in nekaj dejavnosti, ki so na voljo v tisti kategoriji.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Nedan finns en lista över kategorier med några av aktiviteterna tillgängliga i varje kategori.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Aşağıda, bazı etkinliklerin bulunduğu kategorilerin bir listesini bulabilirsiniz.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Нижче наведено список категорій із деякими вправами у цих категоріях.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxBelow you can find a list of categories with some of the activities available in that category.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">下面列出了一些分类和对应分类中的活动。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">下方您可以看到該類別的活動清單。</p>
    <ul>
      <li>computer discovery: keyboard, mouse, different mouse gestures, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">descobrir l'ordinador: teclat, ratolí, diferents gestos del ratolí...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">descobrir l'ordinador: teclat, ratolí, diferents gestos del ratolí...</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Entdeckung des Computers: Tastatur, Maus, verschiedene Mausgesten ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="el">ανακαλύπτω τον υπολογιστή: πληκτρολόγιο, ποντίκι, διάφορες ενδείξεις δείκτη ποντικιού, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">computer discovery: keyboard, mouse, different mouse gestures, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">descubrimiento del ordenador: teclado, ratón, distintos gestos con el ratón...</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">arvuti tundmaõppimine: klaviatuur, hiir, erinevad hiireliigutused ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">tietokoneen oppiminen: näppäimistö, hiiri, eri hiirieleet…</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">découverte de l'ordinateur : clavier, souris, mouvements de la souris…</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Descubrindo o computador: o teclado, o rato, os xestos do rato…</li>
      <li xml:lang="hi">कंप्यूटर की खोज: कीबोर्ड, माउस, अलग माउस इशारों, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">penemuan komputer: keyboard, mos, perbedaan pergerakan mos, ..</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">scoperta del computer: tastiera, mouse, vari gesti con il mouse, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">컴퓨터와 친해지기: 키보드, 마우스, 마우스 제스처, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">ontdekken van de computer: toetsenbord, muis, verschillende muisbewegingen, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="nn">datamaskin: tastatur, mus, ulike muserørsler, …</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">odkrywanie komputera: klawiatura, mysz, różne ruchy myszą, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">descoberta do computador: teclado, rato, os diferentes gestos com o rato, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">conhecendo o computador: teclado, mouse, diferentes movimentações com o mouse, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ro">descoperirea calculatorului: tastatura, mausul, diferite gesturi cu mausul, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ru">знакомство с компьютером: клавиатура, мышь, различные жесты мышью, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">objavovanie počítača: klávesnica, myš, rôzne gestá myši...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">delo z računalnikom: tipkovnica, miška, kretnje miške, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">upptäcka datorn: tangentbord, mus, olika musgester, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">bilgisayarı keşfetme: klavye, fare, farklı fare hareketleri, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Знайомство з комп’ютером: клавіатура, миша, керування мишею…</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxcomputer discovery: keyboard, mouse, different mouse gestures, ...xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">探索电脑：键盘、鼠标、不同的鼠标手势……</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">電腦探索：鍵盤、滑鼠、不同的滑鼠手勢等</li>
      <li>arithmetic: table memory, enumeration, mirror image, balance
    the scale, change giving, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">aritmètica: memoritzar la taula, enumeració, imatge al mirall, equilibrar la balança, donar el canvi...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">aritmètica: memoritzar la taula, enumeració, imatge al mirall, equilibrar la balança, donar el canvi...</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Arithmetik: Kombitabellen, Aufzählungen, Bilder spiegeln, Gewichte ausgleichen, Wechselgeld geben...</li>
      <li xml:lang="el">αριθμητική: μνημονικός πίνακας, απαρίθμηση, κάτοπτρο, ισορροπώ τη ζυγαριά, δίνω ρέστα, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">arithmetic: table memory, enumeration, mirror image, balance the scale, change giving, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">aritmética: memorización de tablas, enumeración, imagen especular, equilibrar la balanza, devolver cambios...</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">aritmeetika: nähtu mäletamine, loendamine, peegelpildid, kaalu tasakaalustamine, raha tagasiandmine...</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">aritmetiikka: kertotaulujen opettelu, laskutehtävät, peilikuvan piirtäminen, vaa’an tasapainottaminen, vaihtorahan antaminen, …</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">arithmétique : apprentissage des tables d'opérations mathématiques, l'énumération, de symétrie d'image, équilibrage de la balance, rendre la monnaie…</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Aritmética: táboas de memoria, enumeracóns, imaxes espello, equilibrar a balanza, dar o cambio…</li>
      <li xml:lang="hi">अंकगणितीय: तालिका मेमोरी, गणण, दर्पण छवि, पैमाने संतुलन, देय परिवर्तन, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">aritmatika: tabel ingatan, pencacahan, cerminan gambar, menyeimbangkan skala, ganti memberi, ..</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">aritmetica: tabelline, enumerazione, immagine speculare, allineare la bilancia, dare il resto, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">산술 연산: 표 기억하기, 배열하기, 그림 뒤집기, 저울 맞추기, 거스름돈 계산하기, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">rekenen: tafels oefenen, reeksen, afbeelding spiegelen, de schaal in evenwicht brengen, wijziging gegeven, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="nn">rekning: gongetabellen, teljing, spegelbilete, måling av vekt, vekslepengar, …</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">arytmetyka: tablice pamięciowe, wyliczanie, obraz lustrzany, wyrównoważanie wagi, wydawanie reszty, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">aritmética: memória da tabuada, enumeração, imagem-espelho, equilíbrio de balanças, trocos, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">matemática: memória matemática, enumeração, imagens espelhadas, balanceamento de escalas, moedas e troco, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ro">aritmetică: tabla înmulțirii, enumerări, imagini în oglindă, echilibrarea balanței, datul restului, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ru">арифметика: игра «память» с подсчётом, счёт, отражение рисунка, уравновешивание весов, подсчёт сдачи, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">aritmetické: tabuľková pamäť, výpočet, zrkalový obrázok, vyváženie mierky, zmena dávky...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">računstvo: spomin z računi, štetje, uravnoteži tehtnico, vračanje drobiža, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">aritmetik: tabellminne, uppräkning, spegelbild, balansera vågen, ge växel, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">aritmetik: tablo belleği, numaralandırma, ayna görüntüsü, ölçeği dengelemek, para üstü, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Арифметика: запам’ятовування таблиць, нумерація, віддзеркалення, балансування масштабу, обчислення решти…</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxarithmetic: table memory, enumeration, mirror image, balance the scale, change giving, ...xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">算数：表格记忆、枚举、镜像、天平、找零……</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">數學運算：表格記憶、列舉、影像映射、平衡、找零計算等</li>
      <li>science: the canal lock, color mixing, gravity concept, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">ciència: blocar el canal, barreja de colors, el concepte de la gravetat...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">ciència: blocar el canal, barreja de colors, el concepte de la gravetat...</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Wissenschaft: Kanalschleuse, Farbmischung, Gravitation,...</li>
      <li xml:lang="el">επιστήμη: σύστημα αλλαγής στάθμης ροής, ανάμειξη χρωμάτων, η έννοια της βαρύτητας, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">science: the canal lock, colour mixing, gravity concept, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">ciencia: la esclusa de un canal, mezcla de colores, concepto de gravedad...</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">loodusteadused: kanali lüüs, värvide segamine, gravitatsiooni mõistmine...</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">tiede: kanavasulku, värien sekoitus, painovoiman käsite…</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">science : fonctionnement d'une écluse, mélange des couleurs, concept de la gravité…</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Ciencia: o bloqueo da canle, mesturar cores, o concepto da gravitación, etc.</li>
      <li xml:lang="hi">विज्ञान: नहर लॉक, रंग मिश्रण, गुरुत्वाकर्षण अवधारणा, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">ilmu pengetahuan: kunci kanal, pencampuran warna, konsep gravitasi, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">scienza: la chiusa del canale, miscelazione dei colori, il concetto di gravità, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">과학: 운하 갑문, 색 섞기, 중력, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">natuurkunde: de sluis, mengen van kleuren, concept van zwaartekracht, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="nn">vitskap: kanalsluse, blanding av fargar, tyngdekraft, …</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">nauka: śluza na kanale, mieszanie barw, poczucie grawitacji, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">ciência: bloqueio de canais, misturas de cores, conceito de gravidade, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">ciência: comporta de canal, mistura de cores, conceito de gravidade, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ro">științe: ecluza unui canal, amestecul culorilor, conceptul de gravitație, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ru">наука: работа судоходного шлюза, смешивание цветов, представление о гравитации, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">veda: zamknutý kanál, miešanie farieb, koncept grvitácie...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">znanost: zapornica kanala, mešanje barv, koncept težnosti ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">vetenskap: kanalslussen, färgblandning, gravitationskonceptet, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">bilim: kanal kilidi, renk karışımı, yerçekimi kavramı, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Наука: шлюзування, змішування кольорів, поняття тяжіння…</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxscience: the canal lock, color mixing, gravity concept, ...xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">科学：运河闸门、颜料色彩混合、重力的概念……</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">科學：顏色混合、重力觀念、運河鎖等等</li>
      <li>games: memory, connect 4, tic tac toe, sudoku, hanoi tower, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">jocs: memòria, connectar 4, tres en ratlla, sudoku, torre de Hanoi...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">jocs: memòria, connectar 4, tres en ratlla, sudoku, torre de Hanoi...</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Spiele: Memory, Vier gewinnt, Tic-Tac-Toe, Sudoku, Türme von Hanoi,...</li>
      <li xml:lang="el">παιχνίδια: μνήμη, τετράδες, τρίλιζα, σουντόκου, πύργος του Ανόι, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">games: memory, connect 4, tic tac toe, sudoku, hanoi tower, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">juegos: memoria, conectar 4, tres en raya, sudoku, torres de hanoi...</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">mängud: mälu, nelja ühendamine, trips-traps-trull, sudoku, Hanoi tornid...</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">pelit: muisti, neljän suora, ristinolla, sudoku, Hanoin tornit…</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">jeux : trouve les paires, puissance 4, morpion, sudoku, la tour d'hanoï…</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Xogos: memoria, catro en liña, pai nai fillo, sudoku, a torre de Hanoi, etc.</li>
      <li xml:lang="hi">खेल: स्मृति, कनेक्ट 4, टिक टैक टो , सुडोकू, हनोई टॉवर, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">permainan: ingatan, menyambung 4, tic tac toe, sudoku, menara hanoi, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">giochi: memory, forza 4, filetto, sudoku, torre di hanoi, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">게임: 메모리 게임, 4개 연결하기, 삼목, 수도쿠, 하노이 탑, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">spellen: geheugenspel, vier verbinden, tic-tac-toe, sudoku, torens van hanoi, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="nn">spel: hugsespel, fire på rad, bondesjakk, sudoku, tårnet i Hanoi, …</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">gry: na pamięć, łączenie czwórek, tic tac toe, sudoku, wieża hanoi, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">jogos: memória, 4 em linha, jogo do galo, sudoku, torres de Hanói, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">jogos: memória, ligue 4, jogo da velha, sudoku, torre de Hanoi, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ro">jocuri: memorie, leagă 4, X și 0, sudoku, turnul hanoi, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ru">игры: память, соедини 4, крестики-нолики, судоку, Ханойская башня, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">hry: pamäť, spojenie 4, tic tac toe, sudoku, hanojská veža...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">igre: spomin, štiri v vrsto, križci in krožci, sudoku, Hanojski stolpi, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">spel: memory, koppla 4, tre-i-rad, sudoku, tornen i Hanoi, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">oyunlar: hafıza, dörtleme, üç taş, sudoku, hanoi kulesi, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Ігри: запам’ятовування, чотири-у-рядок, хрестики-нулики, судоку, ханойські вежі…</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxgames: memory, connect 4, tic tac toe, sudoku, hanoi tower, ...xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">游戏：记忆、四子棋、井子棋、数独、汉诺塔……</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">遊戲：記憶遊戲、四子棋、井字遊戲、數獨、河內塔等等</li>
      <li>reading: reading practice, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">lectura: practicar la lectura...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">lectura: practicar la lectura...</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Lesen: Leseübungen ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="el">ανάγνωση: εξάσκηση στην ανάγνωση, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">reading: reading practice, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">lectura: prácticas de lectura...</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">lugemine</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">lukeminen: lukemisen harjoittelu…</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">lecture : entraînement à la lecture…</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Lectura: práctica de lectura…</li>
      <li xml:lang="hi">पढ़ना: पढ़ना अभ्यास, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">membaca: latihan membaca, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">lettura: esercitare la lettura, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">읽기: 읽기 연습, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">lezen: lezen oefenen, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="nn">lesing: leseøvingar, …</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">czytanie: nauka czytania, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">leitura: exercícios de leitura, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">leitura: prática de leitura, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ro">citire: exerciții de citire, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ru">чтение: упражнение в чтении, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">čítanie: precvičovanie čítania...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">branje: bralna vaja, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">läsning: läsningsövning, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">okuma: okuma egzersizi, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Читання: вправи із читання…</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxreading: reading practice, ...xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">阅读：阅读练习……</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">閱讀：閱讀練習等等</li>
      <li>other: learn to tell time, the braille system, maze, music
    instruments, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">altres: aprendre a dir l'hora, el sistema braille, laberint, instruments musicals...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">altres: aprendre a dir l'hora, el sistema braille, laberint, instruments musicals...</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Sonstiges: Uhrzeit, Braille-System, Labyrinthe, Musikinstrumente ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="el">άλλα: μαθαίνω να λέω την ώρα, το σύστημα braille, λαβύρινθος, μουσικά όργανα, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">other: learn to tell time, the braille system, maze, music instruments, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">otras: aprender a decir la hora, el sistema braille, laberintos, instrumentos musicales...</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">muu: kellaaja väljendamine, Braille'i kiri, labürint, muusikariistad...</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">muuta: kellonajan kertominen, Braille-järjestelmä, sokkelo, soittimet…</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">autre : apprendre à dire l'heure, le système braille, le labyrinthe, les instruments de musique…</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Outros: aprender a dicir as horas, o sistema Braille, labirintos, instrumentos musicais, etc.</li>
      <li xml:lang="hi">अन्य: समय बताओ, ब्रेल प्रणाली, भूलभुलैया, संगीत वाद्ययंत्र, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">lainnya: belajar menceritakan waktu, sistem braille, labirin, alat musik, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">altro: impara a leggere l'ora, il sistema braille, labirinto, strumenti musicali, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">기타: 시간 읽기, 점자, 미로, 악기, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">overig: leren klokkijken, het braille-systeem, doolhof, muziekinstrumenten, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="nn">anna: lær klokka, lær blindeskrift, labyrint, musikkinstrument, …</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">inne: naucz się godzin na zegarze, systemu brajla, labiryntów, instrumentów muzycznych, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">outros: aprender a dizer as horas, o sistema Braille, labirintos, instrumentos musicais, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">outros: aprendendo a ver as horas, o sistema Braille, labirintos, instrumentos musicais, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ro">altele: învață să citești ceasul, sistemul braille, labirint, instrumente muzicale, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="ru">другое: определение времени по часам, шрифт Брайля, лабиринт, музыкальные инструменты, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">iné: ako povedať čas, braillov systém, bludisko, hudobná nástroje...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">ostalo: prepoznavanje časa, brajica, blodnjak, glasbila, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">annat: lära sig klockan, punktskrift, labyrint, musikinstrument, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">diğer: saati söylemeyi öğrenme, braille sistemi, labirent, müzik, enstrümanlar, ...</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Інше: навчання позначенням часу, система Брайля, лабіринти, музичні інструменти…</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxother: learn to tell time, the braille system, maze, music instruments, ...xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">其他：学认钟表、盲文系统、迷宫、乐器……</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">其他：看時間、點字系統、迷宮、認識樂器等等</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Currently GCompris offers in excess of 100 activities and more
    are being developed. GCompris is free software, that means that
    you can adapt it to your own needs, improve it and, most
    importantly, share it with children everywhere.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Actualment el GCompris ofereix més de 100 activitats i encara se'n desenvolupen més. El GCompris és programari lliure, el qual vol dir que podeu adaptar-lo a les vostres pròpies necessitats, millorar-lo i, el més important, compartir-lo amb nens de tot arreu.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Actualment el GCompris ofereix més de 100 activitats i encara se'n desenvolupen més. El GCompris és programari lliure, el qual vol dir que podeu adaptar-lo a les vostres pròpies necessitats, millorar-lo i, el més important, compartir-lo amb nens de tot arreu.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Insgesamt beinhaltet GCompris mehr als 100 Aktivitäten und wird ständig weiterentwickelt. GCompris ist freie Software. Sie haben also die Möglichkeit, sie ihren Bedürfnissen anzupassen und zu verbessern, und gerne auch alle Kinder der Welt von Ihrer Arbeit profitieren zu lassen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="el">Προς το παρόν το GCompris προσφέρει περισσότερες από 100 δραστηριότητες και αναπτύσσονται και άλλες. Το GCompris είναι ελεύθερο λογισμικό, το οποίο σημαίνει ότι μπορείτε να το προσαρμόσετε στις ανάγκες σας, να το βελτιώσετε, και, το σπουδαιότερο, να το μοιραστείτε με παιδιά από όλον τον κόσμο.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Currently GCompris offers in excess of 100 activities and more are being developed. GCompris is free software, that means that you can adapt it to your own needs, improve it and, most importantly, share it with children everywhere.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">En la actualidad, GCompris ofrece más de 100 actividades y hay muchas más en desarrollo. GCompris es software libre, lo que significa que puede adaptarlo a sus necesidades, mejorarlo y, lo que es más importante, compartirlo con los niños de todo el mundo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Praegu pakub GCompris üle 100 tegevuse ja neid tuleb aina juurde. GCompris on vaba tarkvara, mis tähendab, et seda saab kohandada oma vajadustele, täiustada, ja mis peamine, jagada oma täiustusi lastega kogu maailmas.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">GComprisissa on nykyisellään yli sata toimintoa, ja lisää kehitetään. GCompris on vapaata ohjelmistoa, mikä tarkoittaa, että voit muokata sitä tarpeisiisi, parannella sitä ja mikä tärkeintä jakaa sitä lapsille kaikkialla.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Actuellement, GCompris contient plus de 100 activités et d'autres sont en cours de développement. GCompris est un logiciel libre, ce qui veut dire que vous pouvez l'adapter à vos propres besoins, le modifier et, le plus important, le partager avec des enfants où que ce soit.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Actualmente, GCompris ofrece máis de 100 actividades e hai máis en camiño. GCompris é software libre, o que significa que calquera pode adaptalo ás súas propias necesidades, melloralo e, o máis importante, compartilo con nenos de todo o mundo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hi">वर्तमान में जी कॉम्पप्रस 100 गतिविधियों से अधिक प्रदान करता है और अधिक विकसित किए जा रहे हैं। जी कॉम्पप्रस मुफ्त सॉफ्टवेयर है, इसका मतलब है कि आप इसे अपनी आवश्यकताओं के अनुसार अनुकूलित कर सकते हैं, इसमें सुधार कर सकते हैं, और सबसे महत्वपूर्ण बात, इसे हर जगह बच्चों के साथ साझा कर सकते हैं।</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Saat ini GCompris menawarkan lebih dari 100 aktivitas dan masih banyak lagi yang sedang dikembangkan. GCompris adalah perangkat lunak bebas, itu berarti kamu dapat menyesuaikannya dengan kebutuhanmu sendiri, memperbaikinya dan yang terpenting, bagikan dengan anak-anak di mana-mana.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Attualmente GCompris offre più di 100 attività e altre sono in fase di sviluppo. GCompris è software libero, che significa che puoi adattarlo alle tue necessità, migliorarlo e, cosa più importante, condividerlo con tutti i bambini.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">GCompris는 100개 이상의 활동을 포함하고 있으며 더 많은 활동을 개발하고 있습니다. GCompris는 자유 소프트웨어이며, 필요에 따라서 활동을 개선할 수 있으며 전 세계의 사람들과 공유할 수 있습니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Op dit moment biedt GCompris meer dan 100 activiteiten en meer zijn er in ontwikkeling. GCompris is vrije software, dat betekent dat u het kunt aanpassen aan uw eigen behoeften, het verbeteren en, meest belangrijk, het met kinderen overal kun delen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nn">GCompris har over 100 aktivitetar, og fleire vert utvikla. GCompris er fri programvare. Det vil seia at du kan tilpassa spelet slik du ønskjer, forbetra det og dela det med ungar i heile verda.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Obecnie GCompris zapewnia ponad 100 aktywności, a jeszcze więcej jest opracowywanych. GCompris jest darmowym oprogramowaniem, co oznacza, że możesz je dopasować do własnych potrzeb, ulepszać je i co najważniejsze udostępniać je dzieciom.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">De momento, o GCompris oferece mais de 100 actividades, estando ainda mais em desenvolvimento. O GCompris é uma aplicação de 'software' livre, o que significa que o poderá adaptar às suas próprias necessidades, melhorá-lo e, o mais importante, partilhá-lo com as crianças em todo o lado.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Atualmente o GCompris oferece mais de 100 atividades e outras mais estão sendo desenvolvidas. O GCompris é um software livre, o que significa que você pode adaptá-lo para as suas próprias necessidades, melhorá-lo e, mais importante, compartilhar com as crianças de todo o mundo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ro">Momentan GCompris oferă peste 100 de activități și multe altele sunt în lucru. GCompris este software liber, ceea ce înseamnă că poate fi adaptat nevoilor dumneavoastră, îmbunătățit, dar mai ales, partajat cu copii de pretutindeni.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">В настоящее время GCompris содержит более 100 упражнений, и новые находятся в  разработке. GCompris — свободное ПО, и это значит, что вы можете приспособить его для своих нужд, улучшить, а самое главное — поделиться им с детьми во всём мире.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Aktuálne GCompris ponúka vyše 100 aktivít a ďalšie sa vyvíjajú. GCompris je slobodný softvér, čo znamená, že si ho môžete prispôsobiť na vlastné potreby, zlepšiť, a hlavne zdieľať s deťmi všade.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">GCompris trenutno ponuja več kot 100 dejavnosti, še več pa jih je v razvoju. GCompris je prosta programska oprema, kar pomeni, da jo lahko prilagodite po svoje, še pomembneje pa je, da jo lahko delite z otroki širom sveta.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">För närvarande erbjuder GCompris över 100 aktiviteter och ännu fler håller på att utvecklas. GCompris är fri programvara, vilket betyder att man kan anpassa det till sina egna behov, och viktigast av allt, dela det med barn överallt.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Şu anda GCompris 100'den fazla etkinlik sunuyor ve daha fazlasını geliştiriliyor. GCompris bir özgür yazılımdır; bu, onu kendi ihtiyaçlarınıza uyarlayabilir, geliştirebilir ve en önemlisi, her yerde çocuklarla paylaşabileceğiniz anlamına gelir.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">У поточній версії GCompris понад 100 вправ. Розробники постійно працюють над новими вправами. GCompris є вільним програмним забезпеченням, це означає, що ви можете адаптувати програму до власних потреб, покращувати її і, що найважливіше, ділитися вашими творіннями із усіма дітьми.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxCurrently GCompris offers in excess of 100 activities and more are being developed. GCompris is free software, that means that you can adapt it to your own needs, improve it and, most importantly, share it with children everywhere.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">当前 GCompris 提供超过100个活动，还有更多的正在开发中。GCompris 是自由软件，这意味着您可以根据您的需要进行调整、改进，以及最重要的一点，和世界各地的孩子们分享。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">目前 GCompris 提供超過 100 個活動，還有更多正在開發中。GCompris 是一套自由軟體，表示您可以根據您自己的需求來改進，並分享給所有的孩子們。</p>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>GCompris main menu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Menú principal del GCompris</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Menú principal del GCompris</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">GCompris main menu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Menú principal de GCompris</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Menu principal de GCompris</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Menú principal de GCompris</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Menu principale di GCompris</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">GCompris-hoofdmenu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">Hovudmenyen i GCompris</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Główne menu GCompris</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Menu principal do GCompris</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Meniul principal GCompris</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">GCompris-huvudmeny</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Головне меню GCompris</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxGCompris main menuxx</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-TW">GCompris 主畫面</caption>
      <image width="1080" height="720">https://gcompris.net/screenshots-qt/middle/main_menu.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>click_on_letter_up activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Activitat «Fes clic en una lletra en majúscula»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Activitat «Fes clic en una lletra en majúscula»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">click_on_letter_up activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Actividad «Pulsa en una letra mayúscula»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">L'activité « Trouver la lettre majuscule »</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Actividade de premer sobre letras.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">attività clic sulla lettera</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">activiteit klik_op_letter_omhoog</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">«Trykk på ein bokstav»-aktivitet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">aktywność w klikanie liter</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">actividade carregar_na_letra_para_cima</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Clic pe o literă mare</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Aktiviteten klicka på bokstav upp</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Вправа «Натисніть літеру»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxclick_on_letter_up activityxx</caption>
      <image width="1080" height="720">https://gcompris.net/screenshots-qt/middle/click_on_letter_up.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>clockgame activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Activitat «Rellotge d'aprenentatge»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Activitat «Rellotge d'aprenentatge»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">clockgame activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Actividad «Juego del reloj»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">L'activité « Trouver l'heure »</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Actividade de xogo de reloxo.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">attività dell'orologio</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">activiteit klokspel</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">«Lær klokka»-aktivitet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">aktywność z zegarem</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">actividade do jogo do relógio</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Învățarea ceasului clasic</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Aktiviteten klockspel</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Вправа з годинником</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxclockgame activityxx</caption>
      <image width="1080" height="720">https://gcompris.net/screenshots-qt/middle/clockgame.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>color_mix activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Activitat «Barreja els colors de la pintura»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Activitat «Barreja els colors de la pintura»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">colour_mix activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Actividad «Mezcla de colores»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">L'activité « Mélange de la couleur de peinture »</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Actividade de mestura de cores.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">attività miscela di colori</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">activiteit kleurmix</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">Fargeblandingsaktivitet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">aktywność mieszania barw</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">actividade mistura_cores</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Amestecul culorilor de vopsea</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Aktiviteten färgblandning</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Вправа зі змішування кольорів</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxcolor_mix activityxx</caption>
      <image width="1080" height="720">https://gcompris.net/screenshots-qt/middle/color_mix.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>colors activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Activitat «Colors»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Activitat «Colors»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">colours activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Actividad «Colores»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">L'activité « Trouver la couleur »</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Actividade de cores.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">attività dei colori</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">activiteit kleuren</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">Fargeaktivitet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">aktywność barw</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">actividade cores</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Clic pe culoarea cerută</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Aktiviteten färger</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Вправа з кольорами</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxcolors activityxx</caption>
      <image width="1080" height="720">https://gcompris.net/screenshots-qt/middle/colors.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>crane activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Activitat «Construeix el mateix model»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Activitat «Construeix el mateix model»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">crane activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Actividad «Grúa»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">L'activité « Reconstruire le modèle »</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Actividade de grúa.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">attività della gru</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">activiteit kraan</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">Heisekraneaktivitet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">aktywność dźwigu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">actividade grua</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Construiește după model</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Aktiviteten kran</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Вправа з краном</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxcrane activityxx</caption>
      <image width="1080" height="720">https://gcompris.net/screenshots-qt/middle/crane.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>enumerate activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Activitat «Compta els elements»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Activitat «Compta els elements»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">enumerate activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Actividad «Enumeración»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">L'activité « Compter les éléments »</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Actividade de enumerar.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">attività di enumerazione</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">activiteit opnoemen</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">Teljeaktivitet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">aktywność wyliczania</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">actividade numeração</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Numără elementele mulțimilor</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Aktiviteten uppräkning</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Вправа з лічби</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxenumerate activityxx</caption>
      <image width="1080" height="720">https://gcompris.net/screenshots-qt/middle/enumerate.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>fifteen activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Activitat «El joc dels quinze»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Activitat «El joc dels quinze»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">fifteen activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Actividad «Quince»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">L'activité « Le jeu du taquin »</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Actividade de quince.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">attività del quindici</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">activiteit vijftien</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">«Spelet 15»-aktivitet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">aktywność piętnaście</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">actividade quinze</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Mișcă elementele pentru a recrea imaginea</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Aktiviteten femtonspel</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Вправа «П'ятнадцять»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxfifteen activityxx</caption>
      <image width="1080" height="720">https://gcompris.net/screenshots-qt/middle/fifteen.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>hexagon activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Activitat «Hexàgon»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Activitat «Hexàgon»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">hexagon activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Actividad «Hexágono»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">L'activité « Localiser la fraise »</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Actividade de hexágono.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">attività dell'esagono</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">activiteit hexagon</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">Heksagon-aktivitet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">aktywność sześciokąta</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">actividade hexágono</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Găsește căpșuna de sub hexagoane</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Aktiviteten hexagon</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Вправа «Шестикутники»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxhexagon activityxx</caption>
      <image width="1080" height="720">https://gcompris.net/screenshots-qt/middle/hexagon.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>scalesboard activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Activitat «Equilibra correctament la balança»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Activitat «Equilibra correctament la balança»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">scalesboard activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Actividad «Balanzas»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">L'activité « Trouver le poids »</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Actividade de balanza.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">attività della bilancia</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">activiteit bord_met_schalen</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">Vektaktivitet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">aktywność pięciolinii</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">actividade pautas</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Echilibrează talerele balanței</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Aktiviteten vågbord</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Вправа з визначення ваги</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxscalesboard activityxx</caption>
      <image width="1080" height="720">https://gcompris.net/screenshots-qt/middle/scalesboard.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>chess_partyend activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Activitat «Final de la partida d'escacs»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Activitat «Final de la partida d'escacs»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">chess_partyend activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Actividad «Final de partida de ajedrez»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">L'activité « Le jeu des échecs »</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Actividade de xadrez.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">attività degli scacchi</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Activiteit schaakspel_party_einde</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">Sjakk-aktivitet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">aktywność szachowa</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">actividade xadrez_fim_festa</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Învață să finalizezi cu succes partida de șah</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Aktiviteten schack festavslutning</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Гра у шахи</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxchess_partyend activityxx</caption>
      <image width="1080" height="720">https://gcompris.net/screenshots-qt/middle/chess_partyend.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>traffic activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Activitat «Un joc de trencaclosques amb blocs que es desplacen»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Activitat «Un joc de trencaclosques amb blocs que es desplacen»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">traffic activity</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Actividad «Tráfico»</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">L'activité « Sortir la voiture du parking »</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Actividade de tráfico.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">attività del traffico</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">activiteit verkeer</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nn">Trafikk-aktivitet</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">aktywność ruchu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">actividade trânsito</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ro">Descurcă-te și scoate mașina din parcare</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Aktiviteten trafik</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Вправа з керування рухом</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxtraffic activityxx</caption>
      <image width="1080" height="720">https://gcompris.net/screenshots-qt/middle/traffic.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://gcompris.net/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=gcompris</url>
  <url type="help">http://gcompris.net/wiki/Manual</url>
  <url type="donation">https://gcompris.net/buy-en.html</url>
  <url type="translate">http://gcompris.net/wiki/Developer%27s_corner#Translation</url>
  <update_contact>gcompris-devel@kde.org</update_contact>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>gcompris-qt</binary>
  </provides>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="violence-cartoon">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-fantasy">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-realistic">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-bloodshed">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-sexual">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-desecration">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-slavery">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-worship">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="drugs-alcohol">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="drugs-narcotics">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="drugs-tobacco">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-nudity">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-themes">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-homosexuality">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-prostitution">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-adultery">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-appearance">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="language-profanity">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="language-humor">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="language-discrimination">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-info">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-audio">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-location">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-contacts">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="money-purchasing">none</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="money-gambling">none</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
</component>
